Elliot Sonoqui: And recording in progress. Okay, I think it should work and then share your screen. Oh.
Elliot Sonoqui: shouldn't just want to hear us talk.
Elliot Sonoqui: I think so?
Elliot Sonoqui: Yes, so sorry I couldn't hear you.
Elliot Sonoqui: Hello! My name is Steven. I like mint, chocolate, chip, ice cream. That's the best flavor. Okay? So okay, so our git repo is in here
Elliot Sonoqui: it. It doesn't show. But just so
Elliot Sonoqui: I'll just start. I'll just go down. Okay.
Elliot Sonoqui: sometimes, like back end and front end are in totally different. Get repos, but I'm putting them together because it'll make it a lot easier for us. But it looks a lot more complicated.
Elliot Sonoqui: So
Elliot Sonoqui: I'll start from the top back end. So this is like all the back end stuff, and you can think of it as its own separate repo
Elliot Sonoqui: dot eme
Elliot Sonoqui: So in here like I'll put like what variable names we're using.
Elliot Sonoqui: and then y'all will just copy the dot env dot sample because we we don't get commit our env file
Elliot Sonoqui: because it has our secrets. It's like, Yeah.
Elliot Sonoqui: but Dmv, dot, sample is where you just put the variable names. So people know, like
Elliot Sonoqui: what variable names to fill out for the whole program to work.
Elliot Sonoqui: So we'll do that, and then you copy it, and you get rid of the dot sample on your own computer.
Elliot Sonoqui: And then I added, more like, this back end is where we're gonna have like
Elliot Sonoqui: serverjs. And then, like controllers and services. This will be all like node and express stuff.
Elliot Sonoqui: I guess I can go through each file dot get, nor like we'll have like dot env in here. Any line is what does not get committed to do get
Elliot Sonoqui: so.mv is here. Node modules is here like any like giant file that you don't want to save on bitbucket, you put in. Git ignore
Elliot Sonoqui: package. Dot. Json is awesome mainly the scripts thing
Elliot Sonoqui: so here, like you would say, like Npm run test, and it'll do all of this. So you can automate a lot of stuff with scripts
Elliot Sonoqui: that's like the best thing about this Reme is what shows up on the bucket.
Elliot Sonoqui: That's a good place to like. Document everything.
Elliot Sonoqui: Okay. Front end every app usually starts with source. So you can like, ignore these things and just go straight to source
Elliot Sonoqui: man and then react.
Elliot Sonoqui: Start. Okay, index. Dot. Js is like
Elliot Sonoqui: the entry point, the super main entry point. So this is like traditional Javascript that you'll see.
Elliot Sonoqui: And then you'll see here, up.
Elliot Sonoqui: Which is this.
Elliot Sonoqui: And this is just react stuff.
Elliot Sonoqui: Sorry, and then you'll have to learn. React to understand.
Elliot Sonoqui: Oh, Css. Is Css. And then I made more folders here, so I haven't pushed them yet.
Elliot Sonoqui: But we'll we'll have a lot more folders inside of source.
Elliot Sonoqui: So okay, so why source, when you build it like, it's called building.
Elliot Sonoqui: Basically, when you serve a file on a server
Elliot Sonoqui: like somebody like somebody clicks on your app. What they do is they download these files, these like 3 files. It's like HTML, Javascript and Css. They download those to their computer and their browser just reads it and just shows what it looks like.
Elliot Sonoqui: So their their browser can't handle like a bunch of these different files.
Elliot Sonoqui: So building it just compiles everything into one. And that goes into suspicious.
Elliot Sonoqui: It could be public
Elliot Sonoqui: Bill, this kind of stuff.
Elliot Sonoqui: Yeah, like all this random stuff, this is like
Elliot Sonoqui: it was compiled into this. So this is like react. It wouldn't like vanilla Javascript
Elliot Sonoqui: and also minimizes it. So it gets rid of like blank spaces and stuff. So you don't have to
Elliot Sonoqui: send those over the Internet.
Elliot Sonoqui: But yeah, you don't have to worry about this.
Elliot Sonoqui: But we'll it'll give us something very simple.
Elliot Sonoqui: Yeah, like this, like so when we serve it, when we put it on the server and host it. We'll just like upload like 3 files.
Elliot Sonoqui: I'll figure that out.
Elliot Sonoqui: Yeah.
Elliot Sonoqui: Yarn is just Npm. But better, I was having trouble with Npm.
Elliot Sonoqui: This, you don't have to worry about this. This is just saying like version numbers.
Elliot Sonoqui: So when you run like Npm install, it'll install this specific version of this package.
Elliot Sonoqui: So how do we run this whole thing right right now, if I wanted to run it right now, so back end doesn't do anything.
Elliot Sonoqui: yeah, I'll when I build that, I'll show you all how. But with this, okay.
Elliot Sonoqui: so you wanna make sure you're in
Elliot Sonoqui: in that folder, and then we should be. There's no MPM.
Elliot Sonoqui: Don't know. Why did it? Npm, oh, yeah, this.
Elliot Sonoqui: So if you go, need to be in the same level as package. Dot. Json, let's it's there.
Elliot Sonoqui: I don't know.
Elliot Sonoqui: Yeah. Scripts, not oh, Mp.
Elliot Sonoqui: I was also getting this error
Elliot Sonoqui: react wants us to use a framework now, not just react, feel like it's
Elliot Sonoqui: over, complicates it. I'm not sure what's more complicated, making the old stuff work or just going to the new stuff.
Elliot Sonoqui: probably going to the new stuff would be easier. Okay, I just made that decision.
Elliot Sonoqui: But basically, you'll run. Npm, run, start, and it'll start a react app, do that or not.
Elliot Sonoqui: No, it doesn't work.
Elliot Sonoqui: I'm gonna turn this off. Yeah, yeah, we're done.
Elliot Sonoqui: Man. Sorry about yours.